Guide to the John McCarthy Papers SC0524
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2012-055
  - Misc
    - Unfunded Proposals (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - JMC ARPA (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - VTSS Essay (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - CS323 1993 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - CS323 Nonmonotonic Reasoning (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - C323 1994 1 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - CS323 1994 2 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - CS323 W95 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - STS 160 1994 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - STS 160 W95 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Inconvenient Car Trouble, Axioms (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Proving Properties of Programs (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - assorted loose leaves - misc. (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - KQED 88.5FM. Forum: Artificial Intelligence, 2001 Dec 24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Science and Technology in Our Time. Russian. Artificial Intelligence. Ampex Acetate 0.25" x 600', 5" reel., 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - The Beginning of the End, 1947; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - 2 unidentified 3.5" floppy disks, 2 computer media (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Robots. Post production - edited transcription tape. BBC., 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Robots - post production edited TX tape, 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Argonne National Laboratory Engineering Research. "Integral Fast Reactor... Energy for Tomorrow" (22:45), 1993 Mar 19; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 50, Folder 7)
- Additional Material, Acession ARCH-2013-047
  - notes - handwritten, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memos and Reprints - McCarthy (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Misc notes - not JMG (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Old Notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fredkin, McCarthy - Time Sharing (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - LISP Kalah Program (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Probalistic models of games (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aggregation (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Kryloff and Bogoliuboff (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Subject 6.41 course notes (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Introduction to automatic computation (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Subject 6.41 course notes - McCarthy (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Darmouth summer project notes (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - current misc writings (from 1970) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Aggregation (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Automata Studies (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Machine modfications (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Summer research project (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Badges (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The AI problem - hierarchy of topics (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clean up System 15 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - No on 15 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Intro to Turing Machines (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Research notes, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Projects (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - IBM Consultant memos (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Proof Checking (Stanford CS Department) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Advice Taker (Stanford CS Department) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Time-Sharing Notes (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Essays (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - CHESS (Stanford CS Department) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Chemistry 10 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - General Notes (grey notebook) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - General Notes (red notebook) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - General Notes (yellow notebook) (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - General Notes (orange notebook) (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - General Notes (big yellow notebook) (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Folder A: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Sep (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Folder B: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Sep (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Folder C: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Sep (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Folder D: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Sep (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Folder E: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Sep (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Folder F: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Sep (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Folder G: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Sep (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Folder E: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Sep (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Folder A: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Oct (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Folder B: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Oct (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Folder A: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Nov (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Folder B: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Nov (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Folder C: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Nov (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Folder D: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Nov (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Folder E: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Nov (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Folder F: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Nov (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Folder G: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Nov (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Folder A: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Dec (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Folder B: Notes, letters, reports, and various other documents, 2003 Dec (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Chess program, notes on computer program, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - DocDil, CS Brain exercises, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Leith Philip, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - A letter from Vietnam, 1963, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Donald Plichie, 8-Mar-90 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Contexts academic report, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Notes CYCL, Jun-89 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Letter from the University of Maryland, 16-Feb-61 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Letter from the Putnam Mathematics Competition, 18-Jul-56 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Photograph, May-90 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, circa 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Folder B. Various notes, reports, and other documents, Dec-03 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Folder C. Various notes, reports, and other documents, Dec-03 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Folder C. Various notes, reports, and other documents, Jan-04 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Folder B. Various notes, reports, and other documents, Jan-04 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Folder A. Various notes, reports, and other documents, Aug-04 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Songs, various song lyrics, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Old Pocket Notes & Bus Cards, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Martha, notes, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Manuscripts, 1950s-1960s (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - John (Jack) McCarthy Letters and Photos, 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Michael R. Genesereth Academic Papers, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Math Academic Papers: V.I. Arnold and Michael Robert Herman, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Artificial Intelligence Academic Papers: William A. Hoff, Ryszard S. Michalski, Robert E. Stepp, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - SE2 Policy, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Reprints reprints AI - others, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Reprints - Non CS Academic Papers, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Sigma Xi Lecture, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Notes - JME, including math problems and solutions, circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Calculators Notes and Reports, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Civil Defense Papers, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - III Planning Committee Notes and Reports, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - III Technical Advisory Committee Report, 4-Aug-82 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - AIPHIL Book, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - CBCL, Notes and Reports, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Consulting Agreements, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - CS 226, Notes on CS and one academic report, 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Drafts - JME, Academic Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Editors, Command chart, Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Circumscription, academic paper with rough draft and notes, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - GE Talk notes and O.T.S., Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Interell, Reports and Miscellaneous Documents, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - LISP Book, Mar-81 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - MAD-2 Product Planning Meeting notes, 8-Mar-85 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Artificial Intelligence notes, 1980-1985 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - JMC Notes, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Reprints, non-JMC, Academic Reports and Various documents, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - My reprints, Academic reports, pamphlets, and other documents, 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Reprints on Academic reports, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - SE2 Reports and various documents, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Space, work done with NASA, etc, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Winston notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Misc, One correspondence and a resume, Aug-78 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bukovsky, Correspondences, Jul-85 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - SE2, Extensive and lengthy reports, heavy folder, 1974-1984 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Carolyn, Computer reports, 29-Apr-80 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Misc Sci, Reports, 11-Jan-69 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Interference Corporation, all documents, heavy folder, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - John McCarthy, Everything from expense to academic reports to miscellaneous subfolders and documents, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - More Interference, Reports and supplement documents, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - III Stock, Correspondences, pay stubs, miscellaneous documents including some from from Merrill Lynch, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - III, Correspondences, reports, and miscellaneous documents, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - PCC, Various documents but mainly correspondences, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hoover, One memorandum, 30-Sep-83 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - III, Documents, notes, and correspondences, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - III Current, Documents, notes, and correspondences, 1975-1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Issues, report on issues in Computer Science, 10-Oct-73 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Letters and photographs mainly from Russia and reports, 1972 - (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Letters, postcards, and other documents, 1972 - (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Letters and correspondence, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Quasar, Newspaper stories and other reports, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sense issues, reports, newspapers, and other miscellaneous documents, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Shockley newspaper cover story, 30-Sep-70 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - A variety of reports, meeting notes, and miscellaneous documents, 1988 Jan (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers, correspondences, and reports, 1988 Feb (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondences and a variety of reports, 1988 Mar (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondences and a variety of pamphlets, 1988 Apr (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Copy of a newspaper cover story and notes from a Board Meeting with Information International, 1988 May (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - An "Operations Report" and a newspaper editorial, 1988 Jun (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Documents 1-26, A variety of reports, newspapers, and miscellaneous documents, 1988 Jul (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Documents 1-11, A variety of pamphlets, magazines, and miscellaneous documents, 1988 Aug (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Documents 1-16, A variety of correspondences, reports, pamphlets, and miscellaneous documents, 1988 Sep (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Documents 1-12, A variety of reports, proposals, and miscellaneous documents, 1988 Oct (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - A variety of correspondences and scholarly reports, 1988 Nov (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Documents 25-52, A variety of correspondences and scholarly reports, 1988 Dec (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Documents 1-24, A variety of correspondences and scholarly reports, 1988 Dec (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Folder A, A variety of maps, reports, and miscellaneous documents, 1987 Aug (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Folder B, Scans of books, 1987 Aug (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - A variety of reports, pamphlets, and miscellaneous documents, 1987 Aug (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - A variety of reports, pamphlets, and miscellaneous documents, 1987 Aug (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - A variety of correspondences and scholarly reports, 1987 Jul (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - A variety of reports, pamphlets, and miscellaneous documents, 1987 Mar (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - A variety of reports, pamphlets, and miscellaneous documents, 1987 Feb (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Mostly reviews and a couple of magazines, 1987 Jan (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Notes, reports, classroom exams, and various documents, 1986 Dec (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Notes, reports, and various documents, 1986 Nov (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Notes, reports, and various documents, 1986 Nov (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Mostly academic reports, 1986 Nov (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondences, and one notebook ('04), 1989, and 2000s (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - John McCarthy Novel drafts with comments, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Oral History Interview, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Souvenirs, Drafts of an apparent book "A nerd, a woman, and an Imprudent AI.", Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Passports, visas, and other travel documents, 1980s-00s (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Word Spinners, appears to be a draft version of a book, 24-Jul-04 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Inventions, patents and templates for writing patents, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous folder with various documents (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Notebooks (Box 7)
  - Audiovisual material
    - Lecture slides (Box 8)
    - LISP--HOPL talks, 1978 Jun; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 8)
    - McCarthy (part 1), Undated; 8.02; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 8)
    - McCarthy (part 2), Undated; 8.03; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 8)
    - McCarthy (part 3), Undated; 8.04; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 8)
    - McCarthy (part 4), Undated; 8.05; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 8)
    - Computer Forum: Ed Fest I (part 1), 2006 Mar 25; 8.06; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 8)
    - Computer Forum: Ed Fest I (part 2), 2006 Mar 25; 8.07; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 8)
    - Computer Forum: Ed Fest I (part 3), 2006 Mar 25; 8.08; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 8)
    - Computer Forum: Ed Fest II (part 1), 2006 Mar 26; 8.09; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 8)
    - Computer Forum: Ed Fest II (part 2), 2006 Mar 26; 8.10; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 8)
    - Computer Forum: Ed Fest II (part 3), 2006 Mar 26; 8.11; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 8)
  - Computer files
    - Stanford AI Lab (SAILDART) files, 1208 megabyte(s); (59,245 files in 22,343 directories)
    - Access to Energy newsletter archive, 1973-1994; 2 computer file(s) (PDF)
    - WTDS Interviews, KFJC, 2006 Apr 10-13
      - Chowning, John, 2006 Apr 13; 1 computer file(s) (WAV)
      - Engelbart, Douglas C., 2006 Apr 13; 1 computer file(s) (WAV)
      - Markoff, John, 2006 Apr 13; 1 computer file(s) (WAV)
      - McCarthy, John
      - Warren, Jim, 1 computer file(s) (wav)